hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is Jeremy
microkowski and this podcast I help
coaches trainers and mentors scale their
business and make more money and today
I'm doing it with Halston right here
because you know what that's just how
you got to do things sometimes and he's
sleeping he likes to hear my voice when
I talk and so why not he's going to
outgrow this stage eventually I'm going
to take advantage of it while I can now
today what I want to talk about is
eliminating codependency in coaching and
there's this there's this belief that
you need to
um
coddle
your clients and care more about their
success
than they do and that it's
unkind and lacks compassion
to not do this to follow up with
everybody one-on-one to reach out to
everybody to see how they're doing to
see how they're going
that's your choice obviously
but I would I would urge you to lean in
to a different approach
personal responsibility and this applies
to ourselves as well I'm saying this
both to myself to how I'm coaching
reiterating how I coach I don't reach
out to my clients to see how they're
doing
to see how they are their their business
is going now I've actually had some
nasty emails written to me because of
that because people expected that which
by the way I am very clear that I do not
do that
but people have expected that of me and
were disappointed upset angry that I
didn't do that
turns out they weren't a good fit to be
a client
there's this whole sort of split though
in the coaching industry of basically
co-dependent coaches
that
uh over hover and micromanage
everything that their clients do
every activity that they do to make sure
that they're getting results
is toxic
it's
not healthy
it will burn you out and
you're not helping anybody you're just
making people be a leech onto you and
their success
is now your responsibility
you gotta cut this out
I get it if you're a manager or a middle
manager or a CEO of a company
or maybe you have a
an organization that you're running and
you've got staff under you it's a little
different right I've read all the
different leadership books you want to
reach out see how you can support people
things like that like that's an
important thing to do when running a
company when coaching people
your job is to empower people on the
path and journey
of personal development
to not rely on you for their success
caveat to that you definitely want to
offer opportunities for people to reach
out to you
my coaching clients know they can post
in my Facebook group they can send me a
message they can send me an email
my one-on-one clients can DM me my
one-on-one clients can send me a voice
message
now I have Consulting clients that pay
me way more money I do reach out to them
to see how they're doing
but those are few and far between and
those are a much higher level where I'm
writing their copy and running their ads
and doing all that so it's more of a
more of a staff
based relationship versus a coaching
relationship and I refuse in the
coaching relationship to operate that
way
something that I learned from Dan
Kennedy is something that I learned from
my mom
is focus on the people that are getting
the most success in your coaching
business not the ones that are
struggling the most not the quote
unquote least of these that are not
getting value not doing anything not
taking action you'll go crazy in your
head trying to help raise up people
and creating a toxic codependent
relationship with them to where you are
legitimately working harder on their
success than they are it's not a
sustainable business model
at all and so when you set expectations
of
Hey listen
this is how I'm going to act this is how
I'm going to respond I might respond
once a week to you and respond back you
can ask me for help you can ask me for
questions I can give you guidance and
advice
when you operate out of that it's
healthy
because you're expecting people to show
up and ask you questions not for you to
reach out to them to see if they're
doing okay okay
and I've had a lot of people come at me
and even attack me and even tell me that
this teaching
is is harmful to people that getting
people into a into a coaching
relationship and then not coddling them
basically controlling everything that
they're doing
is
is not a good way to do things and I and
I just I disagree with that
there's there's there's there's
literally a opposing viewpoints on this
in the coaching industry that there
there's a there's a solid line I'm on
the side of the lineup I
require personal responsibility from
people that I work with and I will not
show up
with more energy
than they are willing to show up in
their business
I will not show up
following up constantly with my clients
to make sure that they're doing their
work
if they're not doing their work
that's on them and their personal
responsibility to take control of I will
focus on one person who is having the
most success
and how can I help them go to the next
level of success because they have shown
that they are faithful to the system
when people follow my system they get
results
when they do what I say they make a lot
of money
there are some people they get caught up
in their head
whether it be religious beliefs or
whatever that
they can't do what I say and they they
justify inside of their brain this need
to do everything right do everything
perfect
why they can't succeed and then they go
out there and they blame everybody else
they refuse to take personal
responsibility
for their lack of success and it's just
not this is not a game I'm willing to
play
I get it if you grew up
in a house
a family system
maybe a relationship maybe even a church
environment that did this you might
expect that that's what coaching is
supposed to look like
and this is how most people
go into it where they're trying to
manage other people's emotions where
they're trying to manage other people's
choices where they're trying to make
sure that other people are doing what
they should
you gotta cut that crap out my mom made
a post on my my social media post that I
did about this I loved what she said
I'm gonna I'm gonna read it to you
because it was just it was so powerful
pointed and perfect
she said if a client can't monitor their
own growth and check in with themselves
as a matter of good CEO habits
having a coach do it for them actually
reinforces
the employee mindset behavior that most
entrepreneurs need to get past so so if
I did that to coaches I would literally
be reinforcing behavior that is opposite
of what I'm trying to help them overcome
self-governing entrepreneurs make great
clients and build incredible businesses
and that's who I work with those that
are self-governing
those that can follow up on their own
those that don't need me
for their success I can guide them I can
direct them I can give them
opportunities
I can I can provide them the best
training I can give them the answers
when they come ask me
but I'm not going to spend my time and
energy
wondering are they succeeding are they
doing this maybe I should follow up with
them maybe I should call them maybe I
should do a one-on-one call with my
clients that are not succeeding to to
see if I can help raise them up
nope I'd rather they just drop off
disappear and I'll get better clients
and I'll focus more and more and more on
those that produce case studies and this
model
is what produces the most Financial
results I get it you might disagree with
that there are some people they have
gone as far as to tell me they would
rather make less money
and coddle people
because it's the right thing to do and
because it's kind and compassionate
than to do what is effective to bring in
revenue and oftentimes I come in in
organizations
and even Ministries and I've had to tell
them
with a lot of disagreement that this is
not a healthy way to build things but
this is not a good way to grow stuff
that we need to focus on
where the results are coming from
not our feelings
not trying to make everybody feel
welcome you're not going to make
everybody feel welcome and perfect
and a big part of our marketing method
that we use is repelling people that
aren't a good fit finding and
identifying who is not
going to be a buyer in our business what
I look at is who
has upgraded to my coaching program I
have a group coaching program it's two
thousand dollars a year okay
and I look at we've had almost we've had
over 220 people now go through the
program
and I look at
of those people
what do they have in common
what do the ones who because we have a
30 day money back guarantee trial period
of the ones who took me up on that left
and canceled what did they have in
common and so then how can I adjust my
marketing to not attract the ones that
cancel
see I'm not going after trying to solve
why they canceled
it's not my job to the biggest reason
why most people did is they're just too
they realized it was a lot more work
it's too hard and they don't have enough
money to succeed so I've stopped
marketing to people that that's their
excuses
I've stopped marketing to people that
have the inability to make decisions
that are afraid to take action afraid to
move stuff forward and I can bet you
my bit in fact I know for a fact after
being in this industry for 20 years
this is going to be the Catalyst that's
going to grow things
I've had a lot of people come at me tell
me that how I build things this
structure is wrong that's not right
that it's even hurting people
and
at the end of the day
I have my convictions my beliefs my
standards my values about building a
business as well as designing the life
that I want to build
and it that doesn't involve me
spending energy on people
that are
not willing to show up for themselves I
put my energy to those that are willing
to take personal responsibility and take
ownership of their actions and where
they're at to where they eventually
don't need me
to where they eventually don't need me
for their success
and I'm there as a guide and as a mentor
to lead them from where they are to
where they want to be
but I can only meet them halfway
I'm not going to go any further than
that and what that does is that creates
a beautiful
relationship with your clients and
incredible results with the ones that
are willing to cross that threshold
so I hope this has encouraged you if
you're a new coach
if you're starting out you're wondering
man
how does Jeremiah manage his time this
is a huge part of that
and I hope that you take away from this
some wisdom as well
great life everybody and we'll talk soon
have a good one